Savoy Family Genealogical Collection 150
People's Archive, MLK Library
Savoy Family Genealogical Collection
1850-2013
People's Archive, MLK Library
Savoy family
150
1 Linear feet
1 Boxes
Biographical / Historical
The Savoy family is a prominent African American family in the Washington, DC area and can trace its roots to the 1790s. Savoy family members of note include Edward Louis Savoy (1825 - 1866) and his wife, Elizabeth E. Van Rhodia Butler (1827 - 1906), who were free African Americans well before the Civil War and worked on the Underground Railroad; Edward Augustine Savoy (1855 - 1943), State Department employee and namesake of the S. S. Edward A. Savoy; Alfred Kiger Savoy (1883 - 1964), for whom Savoy Elementary School in Southeast Washington, DC is named; and Willard Wilson "Chip" Savoy (1916 - 1976), author of Alien Land.
The original Savoy family gravesite is located at Historic Woodlawn Cemetery. Savoy family members are also buried at Rock Creek Cemetery, Harmony National Cemetery, and Lincoln Memorial Cemetery.
Source(s): Savoy Family Genealogical Collection, various documents
Custodial History
Savoy family descendants Wilbur Joseph Duplessis "Buddy" Rogers III, Lauret Edith Savoy, and Patricia Annette Green Wright contributed to the vast majority of the genealogical research found within this collection, most of which seems to have been completed between 2011 to 2013. Patricia Annette Green Wright then donated the collection to DC Public Library Special Collections in 2013.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of genealogical information related to the Savoy family of Washington, DC, obtained from family members' records and research. It documents members of the Savoy family born between the years of 1794 and 2009; however, most of the material and information within the collection pertains to Savoy family ancestors born between 1794 and 1912. The life of Edward Augustine Savoy (1855 - 1943) is particularly well-documented.
The collection includes materials such as biographical sketches; family trees; timelines; photographs; bound books; and photocopies and printouts of pertinent documents like census records, obituaries and newspaper articles, book excerpts, church records, letters, and text from relevant websites. No original artifacts (only photocopies/prints) appear in the collection.
Genealogy; African Americans; Families; Black persons
- Series 1
  - The Savoy Family, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Census, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alice A. John Butler, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Eliza Savoy, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Anna Mary Savoy Frederick JD Ridgley, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alfred Savoy, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alfred Savoy, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alfred Kiger Savoy Laura J. Wilson, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Edith A Fish Savoy Robert W. Morgan, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Savoy Photographs, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Edward Louis Savoy Elizabeth E.V. Butler, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Edward Augustine Savoy, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 12)